下は　どうだった？
How was the lower level?
俺たち以外　全滅だよ。
Everyone was annihilated except for us.
まだ　サスケの部下が
２人　いるそうだ。
It seems like two of Sasuke's subordinates
are still around here.
そいつを　見なかったか？
Did you see them?
見てないな。
We haven't seen them.
そいつらも
死んだんじゃないか？
They probably died too.
下は　もう　むちゃくちゃだよ。
Everything is a mess down there.
（オキスケ）いや　雲隠れの感知能力者が
その２人の生存を確認し→
No. A Sensory-Type Ninja
from the Hidden Cloud
confirmed that they survived.
我々に　拘束するように頼んで
去っていった。
They asked us to capture them
and then they left.
そ…　そうなんですか。
Oh, is that so?
お前たち…→
You two...
鎧を脱げ。
Remove your armor.
あらら…　バレてたみたい。
Oh my, it seems we've been found out.
（重吾）やはり
あまり　いい案ではなかったな。
Just as I thought,
that wasn't a very good plan.
《ナルト：サクラちゃん…→
Sakura, why did you do
something like that?
なんで　あんなことを…》
サイ。　お前　なんで…。
Sai! What are you doing here?
（カカシ）分身だな。
It's a clone.
（サイ）さっき　サクラが→
I'm going to tell you
君に　言おうとして言えなかった
本当のことを言うよ。
what Sakura really wanted to say earlier,
but couldn't.
本当のこと？
"Really wanted to say"?
ふ～む。
（ヤマト）どういうことだ？　サイ。
What do you mean, Sai?
サクラは　告白しにきたわけじゃない。
Sakura didn't come to
confess her love for you.
木ノ葉の同期メンバーで決めた
あることを言いにきた。
The Hidden Leaf Ninja have
come to a consensus
and I'm here to inform you.
おかしいとは思ってたけど
やっぱ　何か隠してたんだな。
I thought it was strange.
So she was hiding something after all.
♪～
君に言えなかった
サクラの気持も…→
I've come to understand her feelings.
今の僕なら　わかるよ。
Why Sakura couldn't bring
herself to tell you.
サイ　教えてくれ。
あることって…。
Tell me, Sai...
about the consensus.
サスケを　木ノ葉の手で処理する。
The Hidden Leaf will deal with Sasuke.
君の　同期メンバー全員が
そのつもりで動く。
Every one of your comrades is committed
to that and will act accordingly.
kimi wa ima namida nagashita
I can see the tears in your eyes,
nakijakuru kodomo no you ni
you're just like a crying child
tatoe asu ga mienaku natte mo mamoru yo
I'll keep you safe even though I don't know what tomorrow will bring
natsu no sora miagete niranda
I'll stare up to the summer sky
tsuyogatte bakari de namida wa misenai
You act tough, and never show any tears
hontou wa kowai kuseni
But I know you're scared
taisetsu na mono wo ushinawa nu you ni
You keep running so you don't lose what's important
hisshi de hashirinukete kita
We've always survived through the long night
itsu datte nagai yoru wo futari de norikoeta
I'll always be by your side
kono mama issho ni iru kara
So you don't need to act tough
tsuyogatte naide ii nda yo
kimi wa ima namida nagashita
I can see the tears in your eyes,
nakijakuru kodomo no you ni
you're just like a crying child
tatoe asu ga mienaku natte mo susumu yo
We'll keep moving forward
even though we don't know what tomorrow will bring
natsu no sora miagete sakenda
I'll scream up to the summer sky
natsu no sora miagete niranda
I'll stare up to the summer sky
As One's Friend
サスケを　木ノ葉の手で処理する。
The Hidden Leaf will deal with Sasuke.
君の　同期メンバー全員が
そのつもりで動く。
Every one of your comrades is committed
to that and will act accordingly.
サクラちゃんが…→
Did Sakura...
Did Sakura really agree to that?!
本当に　サクラちゃんが
そんなこと　納得したのか！
サクラちゃんは
サスケのことが　大好きなんだぞ！
Sakura loves Sasuke so much!
なのに…　そんなこと…。
And yet...
How could she?!
今回
木ノ葉を襲った　暁の一件で→
After Akatsuki's attack on our village,
木ノ葉の忍たちは→
the Hidden Leaf Ninja can no longer
recognize Sasuke as one of their own,
暁に協力しているサスケを
容認できなくなった。
not after he supported the Akatsuki.
サクラは　バカじゃないし→
Sakura is not a fool.
それぞれの立場や状況が
わからないほど　子供じゃないさ。
She's not a child who wouldn't understand
the difficulty of the situation.
だから君に
どうにか　そのことを伝えようと→
That's why we came here in person
to try to explain it to you.
ここまで　会いにきたんだ。
くっ…。
だったら…　何で俺に→
Then why didn't she just come out
and tell me the truth?
本当のことを
言ってくれなかったんだ！
簡単には　言えないだろうよ。
It wasn't that simple.
You know that.
お前を苦しめることになるのは
わかってる。
She understood how hurt
you would feel.
だからって…。
But still...
サクラは　サスケを　あきらめ
君が好きだと告白することで→
By telling you
she's given up on Sasuke
and declaring her love for you,
君との約束の重荷を解いた。
she was freeing you from the burden
of that promise you made.
((サクラ：ナルト…　私の　一生のお願い！
Naruto, this is a once
in a lifetime request.
(サスケ君を…　サスケ君を連れ戻して！))
Please... bring Sasuke back!
それでも　君は
サスケを助けたいと言った。
And still, you insisted
on rescuing Sasuke.
だから　本当のことを
言えなかったんだと思う。
I believe that's why
she couldn't tell you the truth.
君の気持を考えたからだよ。
Because she was thinking
about your feelings.
それに　君がそう言うことも
おそらく　わかってたんだ。
In fact, she probably expected you
to say that.
君に本当のことを言うのは→
To be honest, Sakura made us promise
not to tell you the truth.
実は　サクラに
口止めされてたんだ。
自分が
どうにか伝えるって言ってね。
She said she would tell you somehow.
それが　自分の役目だと言ってた。
She said it was her duty to do so.
しかし　ナルトのリアクションが
わかってたなら→
But if she was expecting
Naruto's reaction,
はなから　本当のことを言う
つもりはなかったってことだろ。
she never intended to
tell him the truth, right?
サクラは　どうするつもりだ？
What is Sakura planning to do?
ここからは　僕の想像ですが→
This is just an assumption on my part.
おそらく　サクラは…。
But I believe Sakura...
一人で　サスケを殺すつもりだな。
She intends to kill Sasuke herself.
そうなのか？　サイ！
Is that true, Sai?!
おそらく。
Probably.
((一人で　いろいろ
抱え込まないでください。
Please don't take it all on yourself.
僕も　同じ第七班です。
I feel the same way as you.
それに　みんなも…。
うん。
So does everyone else.
Oh... yeah.
ありがとう　サイ。
Thank you, Sai.
(私も　そのつもりだから))
I know.
サクラは笑って　みんなと協力すると
言ってましたが→
Sakura smiled and told everyone
she would cooperate.
それが作り笑いだと
今度は見抜けましたから。
But this time,
I saw through her fake smile.
ウソだ…
サクラちゃんが　そんなことを。
No way.
Sakura wouldn't do such a thing.
サクラちゃんは　サスケのことが
あんなに…。
She's crazy about Sasuke—
大好きだからこそ
このまま悪へ突き進むサスケを→
It's because she loves him so much
that she can't bear to watch
Sasuke turn more and more evil.
放ってはおけないんだと思う。
大好きだからこそ　そのサスケを
悪の道から救いたいと思ってる。
It's because she loves him so much
that she wants to save Sasuke
from this path of evil.
その方法が
大好きな人を自分の手で→
Even if that means killing the one
she loves with her own hands.
殺めなければならないことに
なるとしても→
それが　サスケを好きになった
彼女なりの覚悟なんだと思う。
That is how committed she is
to her love for Sasuke.
そして　そのことで　ナルト…。
And in doing so, Naruto...
君に恨まれる覚悟もしている。
She's prepared to accept your hatred.
それが　君に一生の重荷を
背負わせようとした→
It's her way of atoning for
the lifelong burden she placed on you.
償いでもあると思っているんだよ。
サクラは　今まで君に頼りすぎた。
Until now, Sakura relied on you too much.
だから今度は　自分一人で
すべてをやろうとしている。
This time, she intends to resolve
everything alone.
サイ…　なんで
俺に　それを話してくれた？
Sai...
Why are you telling me all this?
((サイ：ナルトを苦しめてるのは
サスケだけど→
Sasuke is the source of Naruto's agony.
(君もなんじゃないのかい？))
But aren't you a part of it too?
僕の意でなかったとはいえ
そうサクラを仕向けてしまったのは→
It wasn't my intention,
but I'm partly to blame for
provoking Sakura.
僕のせいでもあるから。
だから　君に言ってしまった。
That's why I told you.
サクラを放っておけなかったし…
僕は　第七班のひとりだから。
I couldn't ignore what Sakura's doing.
And besides, I belong to Team 7.
そうか…。
I see.
《このことを知った
ナルトの胸中は　ゴチャゴチャだな。
Having learned all this,
Naruto must be in turmoil.
さて　どうしたものか》
Now then... What to do?
（テマリ）お前たちに　すぐに
聞いてもらわなければ→
There is something
you must hear immediately.
ならないことがある。
五影会談で何があったか→
We will tell you everything that happened
at the Five Kage Summit.
すべて話す。
（マダラ）久しぶりだな　ダンゾウ。
It's been a long time, Danzo.
うちはの事件以来だな。
We haven't met since
the Uchiha incident.
（ダンゾウ）フー　トルネ…　援護しろ。
Fuu, Torune, assist me.
右腕の封を解く。
I'm going to break the seal
on my right arm.
やつを引きつけておくのだ。
Keep him occupied.
やる気だな…　ダンゾウ…。
So you're going for it, Danzo?
マダラ…　やつの能力は未知だ。
Madara... His abilities are limitless.
用心しろ。
（２人）はっ！
Be careful.
（フー）トルネ。　常に
互いを援護しつつ　攻める。
– Yes, sir.
Torune, we'll back each other up
and attack.
（トルネ）わかっている。
I know.
《心転身の…》
Mind Transfer...
柱の中へ消えた。
He disappeared into the pillar.
やはり　物体をすり抜ける
能力はあるようだ。
It seems he can slip
through objects after all.
それで　どうだ？
Well? Are you able to sense his chakra?
今のやつのチャクラは
感知できてるか？
いや…　完全に消えている。
No. He has completely disappeared.
感知と心転身の術…。
A Sensory-Type with Mind Transfer skills.
山中一族の者か。
A member of the Yamanaka Clan, huh?
身を守るために　相手の攻撃を
すり抜けさせるときは→
In order to protect himself,
he de-materializes his body
at the moment of an attack
やつの体すべてが
実体をなくすようだな。
and passes right through it.
攻撃のために
物理的接触をもつときは→
But he solidifies his body to make
physical contact when he attacks.
実体化する。
つまり　カウンターを狙えばいい。
We have to aim for the counterattack.
よく理解した。　いい分析だ。
That was a well thought out analysis.
カウンターのタイミングを意図的に作る。
The counterattack must
be timed perfectly.
俺たちの攻撃を
連続で仕掛け→
We'll attack one after the other
and get him on the second stage.
２段階で行う。
１段目は　囮役だ。
The first stage will be a diversion.
囮役は俺がやる…。
I'll be the decoy.
心転身の術は読まれているしな。
He's already seen through
my Mind Transfer Jutsu.
お前の術　メインでいく。
わかった。
We'll go with your jutsu.
Got it.
《あの手…》
That technique...
トルネ…　あの術を…。
Torune... That jutsu...
《ここだ！》
Now!
こいつ…
攻撃するフリをして　わざと…。
This guy...
He just pretended to attack.
くそ…　引っかけられた…。
Damn it. We fell for it!
ほぅ…　チャクラを流し込んで→
Hmm...
細胞を破壊する術か…
厄介だな。
A jutsu to flush in chakra
and destroy cells?
How troublesome.
すまない　フー…
すぐに取り除く。
Forgive me, Fuu.
I'll extract them right away.
チャクラじゃないな…。
This isn't chakra.
（マダラ）これは　ナノサイズの毒蟲…。
These are nano-sized venom beetles.
細菌に近いな。
They are almost like bacteria.
触れると瞬時に
細胞を侵食していく蟲…。
Insects that devour cells on contact.
フッ…　聞いたことがある。
I've heard of them.
お前　油女一族の中でも
秘伝忍術を持つ忍だな。
You are a ninja from the Aburame Clan
who knows Hidden Ninjutsu.
そうか　その蟲の抗体を持つ
油女シクロのガキか。
I see. You're the son
of Shikuro Aburame,
the one with immunity to those insects.
根にいたとはな。
To think you were in the Foundation.
ダンゾウ　いい部下を揃えたな。
Danzo!
You have yourself a good subordinate.
トルネ　すまない。
フー　気を抜くな。
Forgive me, Torune.
Don't blame yourself, Fuu.
すぐにやつの出所を感知しろ。
Use your sensors to
locate him quickly.
次でケリをつける。
I'll get him the next time.
クソッ！
Damn it!
《トルネごと吸い込んだだと！？》
He sucked in Torune!
右腕が毒蟲に感染してしまったな。
My right arm has been injected
with the venom beetles.
次は　お前だ！
You're next.
そうか　そこまで
荒れた会談になったとはね。
I see.
Who would have thought the meeting
would become so intense.
やはり　ダンゾウでは…。
I guess with Danzo...
俺は火影ってのは
あまり乗り気じゃないんだけどさ。
I'm not too eager about
becoming the Hokage.
状況がこれじゃあ
仕方ないとしても…。
And even if the situation
requires me to accept...
木ノ葉に帰って　みんなの意見を
聞かないことには→
I'll have to return to
Hidden Leaf Village first
話にならないよ。
and hear what the others say.
マダラが戦争を仕掛けてくるって
宣言してんだぞ。
Madara has declared war on us!
悠長なこと言ってられないだろ。
There's no time to deliberate.
おそらく　みんなの同意は
すぐに得られると思います。
I'm sure everyone will approve.
カカシ先輩が火影ってことで→
We should have them proceed
on the premise
話を進めておいてもらいましょう。
that you are the Hokage, Kakashi.
対応が遅くなって
暁やマダラに先手を打たれ→
If our response is delayed
and the Akatsuki and Madara
take the advantage,
後手に回ってしまうほうが
やばいですから。
that would be even worse.
まぁ　そうなるか　どうも。
I guess you're right. Thanks.
それとサスケですね。
And Sasuke...
ふぅ　会談まで
襲撃するようになるとは…。
For him to attack the summit...
（我愛羅）ナルト　言っておくが
これは八尾と九尾。
Naruto, this is a battle to protect
the Eight-Tails and the Nine-Tails.
つまり　お前を守る戦争でもある。
Namely you.
そして忍の世界のため→
And it's also for the ninja world.
風影として
俺は命がけでお前を守る。
As the Kazekage,
I would give my life to protect you.
暁の配下として→
If Sasuke Uchiha confronts
うちはサスケが俺たち忍連合の前に
立ちはだかるなら→
the Allied Shinobi Forces
as a member of the Akatsuki,
容赦はしない。
I will show no mercy.
((サスケ　お前は俺と似ている。
Sasuke, you and I are alike.
この世の闇を歩いてきた者。
We've both walked through
the darkness of this world.
だからこそ　小さな光明ですら
目に届くはずだ。
That's why you should be able to see
even the faintest glimmer of light.
昔も　そして今も…。
In the past and even now.
（サスケ）俺は　とっくに目を閉じた。
I closed my eyes long ago.
(俺の目的は闇の中にしかない))
My goals exist only in the darkness.
サスケは
お前を見ようとはしていない。
Sasuke doesn't care about you.
自ら闇を求めている。
All he wants is darkness.
ナルト。
お前は俺に
自分は火影になる男だと言ったな。
Naruto, you told me,
"I am going to be the Hokage."
俺は風影になった。
I have become the Kazekage.
影の名を
背負う覚悟を決めたなら→
If you are prepared to bear
the burden of being a Kage,
サスケの友として　お前が
本当にやるべきことをやれ。
then do what is right
as Sasuke's friend.
伝えることは
すべて伝えた。
We've said everything we needed to say.
帰るぞ　我愛羅。
Let's go, Gaara.
では　これで
私らは　里へ帰る。
We will return to our village.
はたけカカシ　あなたが
火影になるものとして砂は動く。
Kakashi Hatake...
With the understanding that
you will be Hokage,
the Sand will take action.
（テマリ）同盟国として
情報の混乱がないよう願う。
As allied nations,
I pray that there will be
no conflicting intel between us.
了解した。
Understood.
俺は　お前を友だと思っている。
I consider you my friend.
かつての俺にとって
友とは　ただの言葉。
In the past,
"friend" was merely a word to me.
それ以上でも
それ以下でもなかった。
Nothing more, nothing less.
だが　お前と会って
気づかされた。
But after meeting you,
you made me realize that...
大切なのは
その言葉の意味だと。
the meaning of that word
is what's important.
その意味するところが
なんなのか→
What does it mean?
お前は　サスケのために
何をしてやれるのか。
What can you do for Sasuke?
Think hard about that.
よく考えろ。
行くぞ。
Let's go.
ナルト…。
Naruto...
自分で答えを
出すしかないよ。
Let him find the answer himself.
（香燐）こんな暗いところで
サスケと２人…。
Here I am, all alone with Sasuke
in this dark place.
ムラムラを抑えて
あんたの面倒　見てやってんだ。
Taking care of you while resisting
every urge in my body.
いいかげん　回復しやがれ。
Hurry up and get well!
ヒッ！　大丈夫なのかよ？
サスケ。
A-Are you all right, Sasuke?
《また　冷たく
変わりゃしないだろうな…》
Cold as ever. He'll never change.
《でも　やっぱり…》
But... still...
ここから出せ。
Let me out of here.
そう慌てるな。
今　ここから出してやる。
Don't be so hasty.
I'll let you go.
外には　お前への土産もある。
I have something for you outside.
うちはサスケか…。
Sasuke Uchiha.
お前は　さがっていろ。
巻き込まれれば死ぬぞ。
You stay back.
If you get involved, you'll die.
ちょうどいい…。
Perfect.
サスケ　マダラ。
Sasuke... Madara...
お前たちの写輪眼も
いただくとしよう。
I'll take both your Sharingan.
te ashi tsunagareteru yo i'm like marionetto
My hands and feet are tied up, I'm Like a marionette
sonna no arienee yo ittai dounatteru yo
This is nonsense, What's going on?
tell me tell me who's the ruler? kiyasuku sawaruna
(Tell Me Tell Me) Who's the Ruler?
Don't put your hands on me
kikitakuneeyo mou kiben wa
I don't want to hear your false arguments anymore
kokkara sakiwa ore ga kimen da!
I'm in charge of my own life from now on
mienai kusari wo tachikire
Break the invisible chains
genkai sure sure dashikire
Test your limits
jibun de kachi toranakya
If you don't win it for yourself
darekano te ni watacchauze
Someone else will take it
stand up! saa mina reach out for liberty
Stand Up!! C'mon everybody Reach Out For Liberty
ima ga ugokidasu toki da
It's time to make a move
wake up! saa mina step up shite sakebe
Wake Up!! C'mon everybody Step Up and shout
oh yes we are the dreamer
run for your freedom
saki datsu mono nante nakutatte
Even though you don't have a reason
run for your freedom
yume no tobira kettobashite
Kick the door to your dream
so you better stand up!! saa mina reach out for liberty
(so you better) Stand Up!!
C'mon everybody Reach Out For Liberty
ima ga ugokidasu toki da
It's time to make a move
wake up! saa mina step up shite sakebe
Wake Up!! C'mon everybody Step Up and shout
oh yes we are the dreamer
run for your freedom
saki datsumono nante nakutatte
Even though you don't have a reason
run for your freedom
yume no tobira ketto bashite
Kick the door to your dream
fight for your freedom
Next Episode
Let me ask one thing.
Is it true that Itachi Uchiha eliminated my clan by order of the Elders?
＜今日から７代目＞
As I thought, you were special.
＜季節のご飯が大好きな豆助＞
Damn Itachi! I see he revealed everything to you before he died.
≫はーい　おまたせ
できたわよ
Next time on Naruto Shippuden: "Danzo's Right Arm"
Danzo's Right Arm
Don't say anymore about Itachi!
＜　それは魚の王様・鯛のうまみが→